<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.07944v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2022-05-16T19:05:27Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2022-05-16T19:05:27Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Design and Implement an Enhanced Simulator for Autonomous Delivery Robot</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  As autonomous driving technology is getting more and more mature today,
autonomous delivery companies like Starship, Marble, and Nuro has been making
progress in the tests of their autonomous delivery robots. While simulations
and simulators are very important for the final product landing of the
autonomous delivery robots since the autonomous delivery robots need to
navigate on the sidewalk, campus, and other urban scenarios, where the
simulations can avoid real damage to pedestrians and properties in the real
world caused by any algorithm failures and programming errors and thus
accelerate the whole developing procedure and cut down the cost. In this case,
this study proposes an open-source simulator based on our autonomous delivery
robot ZebraT to accelerate the research on autonomous delivery. The simulator
developing procedure is illustrated step by step. What is more, the
applications on the simulator that we are working on are also introduced, which
includes autonomous navigation in the simulated urban environment, cooperation
between an autonomous vehicle and an autonomous delivery robot, and
reinforcement learning practice on the task training in the simulator. We have
published the proposed simulator in Github.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhaofeng Tian</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weisong Shi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.07944v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2205.07944v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  