<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11237v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2022-10-19T10:04:33Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2022-10-19T10:04:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Emerging Threats in Deep Learning-Based Autonomous Driving: A
  Comprehensive Survey</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Since the 2004 DARPA Grand Challenge, the autonomous driving technology has
witnessed nearly two decades of rapid development. Particularly, in recent
years, with the application of new sensors and deep learning technologies
extending to the autonomous field, the development of autonomous driving
technology has continued to make breakthroughs. Thus, many carmakers and
high-tech giants dedicated to research and system development of autonomous
driving. However, as the foundation of autonomous driving, the deep learning
technology faces many new security risks. The academic community has proposed
deep learning countermeasures against the adversarial examples and AI backdoor,
and has introduced them into the autonomous driving field for verification.
Deep learning security matters to autonomous driving system security, and then
matters to personal safety, which is an issue that deserves attention and
research.This paper provides an summary of the concepts, developments and
recent research in deep learning security technologies in autonomous driving.
Firstly, we briefly introduce the deep learning framework and pipeline in the
autonomous driving system, which mainly include the deep learning technologies
and algorithms commonly used in this field. Moreover, we focus on the potential
security threats of the deep learning based autonomous driving system in each
functional layer in turn. We reviews the development of deep learning attack
technologies to autonomous driving, investigates the State-of-the-Art
algorithms, and reveals the potential risks. At last, we provides an outlook on
deep learning security in the autonomous driving field and proposes
recommendations for building a safe and trustworthy autonomous driving system.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hui Cao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenlong Zou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yinkun Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ting Song</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mengjun Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>28 pages,10 figures</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11237v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2210.11237v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
