<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/cond-mat/0102536v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2001-02-28T20:12:09Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2001-02-28T20:12:09Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Impact of Electron-Electron Cusp on Configuration Interaction Energies</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The effect of the electron-electron cusp on the convergence of configuration
interaction (CI) wave functions is examined. By analogy with the
pseudopotential approach for electron-ion interactions, an effective
electron-electron interaction is developed which closely reproduces the
scattering of the Coulomb interaction but is smooth and finite at zero
electron-electron separation. The exact many-electron wave function for this
smooth effective interaction has no cusp at zero electron-electron separation.
We perform CI and quantum Monte Carlo calculations for He and Be atoms, both
with the Coulomb electron-electron interaction and with the smooth effective
electron-electron interaction. We find that convergence of the CI expansion of
the wave function for the smooth electron-electron interaction is not
significantly improved compared with that for the divergent Coulomb interaction
for energy differences on the order of 1 mHartree. This shows that, contrary to
popular belief, description of the electron-electron cusp is not a limiting
factor, to within chemical accuracy, for CI calculations.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>David Prendergast</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>Department of Physics</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>M. Nolan</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>NMRC, University College, Cork, Ireland</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Claudia Filippi</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>Department of Physics</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Stephen Fahy</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>Department of Physics</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>J. C. Greer</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>NMRC, University College, Cork, Ireland</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:doi>10.1063/1.1383585</ns1:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.1383585" rel="related" />
    <ns1:comment>11 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables, LaTeX209, submitted to The Journal of
  Chemical Physics</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:journal_ref>J. Chem. Phys. 115, 1626 (2001)</ns1:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/cond-mat/0102536v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/cond-mat/0102536v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  