<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16887v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-10-22T10:45:05Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-10-22T10:45:05Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Distribution of Responsibility During the Usage of AI-Based Exoskeletons
  for Upper Limb Rehabilitation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The ethical issues concerning the AI-based exoskeletons used in healthcare
have already been studied literally rather than technically. How the ethical
guidelines can be integrated into the development process has not been widely
studied. However, this is one of the most important topics which should be
studied more in real-life applications. Therefore, in this paper we highlight
one ethical concern in the context of an exoskeleton used to train a user to
perform a gesture: during the interaction between the exoskeleton, patient and
therapist, how is the responsibility for decision making distributed? Based on
the outcome of this, we will discuss how to integrate ethical guidelines into
the development process of an AI-based exoskeleton. The discussion is based on
a case study: AiBle. The different technical factors affecting the
rehabilitation results and the human-machine interaction for AI-based
exoskeletons are identified and discussed in this paper in order to better
apply the ethical guidelines during the development of AI-based exoskeletons.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name> Huaxi</ns0:name>
      <ns1:affiliation>Yulin</ns1:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name> Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Melanie Fontaine</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Marianne Huchard</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Baptiste Mereaux</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Olivier Remy-Neris</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>Robot Trust for Symbiotic Societies (RTSS) at IROS 2022</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16887v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2410.16887v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="Computer science" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
