<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2409.03193v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-09-05T02:33:48Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-09-05T02:33:48Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Upper-Limb Rehabilitation with a Dual-Mode Individualized Exoskeleton
  Robot: A Generative-Model-Based Solution</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Several upper-limb exoskeleton robots have been developed for stroke
rehabilitation, but their rather low level of individualized assistance
typically limits their effectiveness and practicability. Individualized
assistance involves an upper-limb exoskeleton robot continuously assessing
feedback from a stroke patient and then meticulously adjusting interaction
forces to suit specific conditions and online changes. This paper describes the
development of a new upper-limb exoskeleton robot with a novel online
generative capability that allows it to provide individualized assistance to
support the rehabilitation training of stroke patients. Specifically, the
upper-limb exoskeleton robot exploits generative models to customize the fine
and fit trajectory for the patient, as medical conditions, responses, and
comfort feedback during training generally differ between patients. This
generative capability is integrated into the two working modes of the
upper-limb exoskeleton robot: an active mirroring mode for patients who retain
motor abilities on one side of the body and a passive following mode for
patients who lack motor ability on both sides of the body. The performance of
the upper-limb exoskeleton robot was illustrated in experiments involving
healthy subjects and stroke patients.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yu Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shu Miao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jing Ye</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Gong Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jianghua Cheng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ketao Du</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiang Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2409.03193v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.03193v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  