<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.02200v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2020-06-05T14:56:50Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2019-07-04T03:14:29Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Design and Evaluation of Torque Compensation Controllers for a Lower
  Extremity Exoskeleton</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this paper, we present an integrated human-in-the-loop simulation paradigm
for the design and evaluation of a lower extremity exoskeleton that is
elastically strapped onto human lower limbs. The exoskeleton has 3 rotational
DOFs on each side and weighs 23kg. Two torque compensation controllers of the
exoskeleton are introduced, aiming to minimize interference and maximize
assistance to human motions, respectively. Their effects on the wearer's
biomechanical loadings are studied with a running motion and predicted ground
reaction forces. It is found that the added weight of the passive exoskeleton
substantially increases the wearer's musculoskeletal loadings. The maximizing
assistance controller reduces the knee joint torque by almost a half when
compared to the passive exoskeleton and the resultant torque is only 72% of
that from the normal running without exoskeleton. When compared to the normal
running, this controller also reduces the hip flexion and extension torques by
31% and 38%, respectively. As a result, the peak activations of the biceps
short head, gluteus maximus, and rectus femoris muscles are reduced by more
than a half. Nonetheless, the axial knee joint reaction force increases for all
exoskeleton cases due to the added weight and higher GRFs. In summary, the
results provide sound evidence of the efficacy of these two controllers on
reducing the wearer's musculoskeletal loadings when compared to the passive
exoskeleton. And it is shown the human-in-the-loop simulation paradigm
presented here can be used for virtual design and evaluation of powered
exoskeletons and pave the way for building optimized exoskeleton prototypes for
experimental evaluation.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xianlian Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xinyu Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>44 pages, 11 figures, 3 tables</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.02200v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1907.02200v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="70E60" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="H.1.2" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  