<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06772v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2023-07-03T17:20:09Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2023-05-11T12:52:36Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Control of a Back-Support Exoskeleton to Assist Carrying Activities</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Back-support exoskeletons are commonly used in the workplace to reduce low
back pain risk for workers performing demanding activities. However, for the
assistance of tasks differing from lifting, back-support exoskeletons potential
has not been exploited extensively. This work focuses on the use of an active
back-support exoskeleton to assist carrying. Two control strategies are
designed that modulate the exoskeleton torques to comply with the task
assistance requirements. In particular, two gait phase detection frameworks are
exploited to adapt the assistance according to the legs' motion. The two
strategies are assessed through an experimental analysis on ten subjects.
Carrying task is performed without and with the exoskeleton assistance. Results
prove the potential of the presented controls in assisting the task without
hindering the gait movement and improving the usability experienced by users.
Moreover, the exoskeleton assistance significantly reduces the lumbar load
associated with the task, demonstrating its promising use for risk mitigation
in the workplace.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Maria Lazzaroni</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Giorgia Chini</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Francesco Draicchio</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christian Di Natali</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Darwin G. Caldwell</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jesús Ortiz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>in-press article, accepted for 2023 IEEE International Conference on
  Rehabilitation Robotics (ICORR)</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06772v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2305.06772v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  