<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20094v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-07-29T15:23:35Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-07-29T15:23:35Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Orbital Angular Momentum Active Anti-Jamming in Radio Wireless
  Communications</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Orbital angular momentum (OAM), providing the orthogonality among different
OAM modes, has attracted much attention to significantly increase spectrum
efficiencies (SEs) and enhance the anti-jamming results of wireless
communications. However, the SE of wireless communications is severely degraded
under co-frequency and co-mode hostile jamming. Focused on this issue, we
propose a novel OAM active anti-jamming scheme to significantly enhance the
anti-jamming results of wireless communications under broadband hostile
jamming. Specifically, the OAM transmitter with energy detection senses jamming
signals to identify which OAM modes are jammed and unjammed. Based on the
recognition of OAM modes, useful signals are modulated by reflecting the
received co-frequency and co-mode jamming signals with the assistance of a
programmable gain amplifier (PGA) to the OAM receiver, thus utilizing both the
OAM modes jammed by hostile attacks and the energy of jamming signals.
Meanwhile, the unjammed OAM modes allocated with total transmit power are
multiplexed for useful signal transmission. Numerical results demonstrate that
our proposed OAM active anti-jamming scheme can achieve high OAM mode
utilization and significantly increase the SEs.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kexin Zheng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenchi Cheng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Liping Liang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>5 pages, 3 figures and accepted by Ucom 2024</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20094v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2407.20094v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  