<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.07613v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2019-04-16T12:07:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2019-04-16T12:07:43Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Jam Sessions: Analysis and Experimental Evaluation of Advanced Jamming
  Attacks in MIMO Networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In advanced jamming, the adversary intentionally concentrates the available
energy budget on specific critical components (e.g., pilot symbols,
acknowledgement packets, etc.) to (i) increase the jamming effectiveness, as
more targets can be jammed with the same energy budget; and (ii) decrease the
likelihood of being detected, as the channel is jammed for a shorter period of
time. One of the fundamental challenges in designing defense mechanisms against
an advanced jammer is understanding which jamming strategies yields the lowest
throughput, for a given channel condition and a given amount of energy. To the
best of our knowledge, this problem still remains unsolved. To fill this gap,
in this paper we conduct a comparative analysis of several most viable advanced
jamming schemes in the widely-used MIMO networks. We first mathematically model
a number of advanced jamming schemes at the signal processing level, so that a
quantitative relationship between the jamming energy and the jamming effect is
established. Based on the model, theorems are derived on the optimal advanced
jamming scheme for an arbitrary channel condition. The theoretical findings are
validated through extensive simulations and experiments on a 5-radio 2x2 MIMO
testbed. Our results show that the theorems are able to predict jamming
efficiency with high accuracy. Moreover, we show that the theorems can be
incorporated to state-of-art reinforcement learning based jamming algorithms
and boost the action exploration phase so that a faster convergence is
achieved.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Liyang Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Francesco Restuccia</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tommaso Melodia</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Scott M. Pudleswki</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>To appear at ACM MobiHoc 2019, Catania, Italy</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.07613v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1904.07613v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  