<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.02756v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-01-10T19:02:08Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2017-01-10T19:02:08Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Applications of Nuclear Physics</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Today the applications of nuclear physics span a very broad range of topics
and fields. This review discusses a number of aspects of these applications,
including selected topics and concepts in nuclear reactor physics, nuclear
fusion, nuclear non-proliferation, nuclear-geophysics, and nuclear medicine.
The review begins with a historic summary of the early years in applied nuclear
physics, with an emphasis on the huge developments that took place around the
time of World War II, and that underlie the physics involved in designs of
nuclear explosions, controlled nuclear energy, and nuclear fusion. The review
then moves to focus on modern applications of these concepts, including the
basic concepts and diagnostics developed for the forensics of nuclear
explosions, the nuclear diagnostics at the National Ignition Facility, nuclear
reactor safeguards, and the detection of nuclear material production and
trafficking. The review also summarizes recent developments in nuclear
geophysics and nuclear medicine. The nuclear geophysics areas discussed include
geo-chronology, nuclear logging for industry, the Oklo reactor, and
geo-neutrinos. The section on nuclear medicine summarizes the critical advances
in nuclear imaging, including PET and SPECT imaging, targeted radionuclide
therapy, and the nuclear physics of medical isotope production. Each subfield
discussed requires a review article onto itself, which is not the intention of
the current review. Rather, the current review is intended for readers who wish
to get a broad understanding of applied nuclear physics.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Anna C. Hayes</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:doi>10.1088/1361-6633/80/2/026301</ns1:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1361-6633/80/2/026301" rel="related" />
    <ns1:journal_ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 80 (2017) 026301</ns1:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.02756v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1701.02756v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="nucl-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  