<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.09323v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2022-04-20T08:58:35Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2022-04-20T08:58:35Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Self-supervised Learning for Sonar Image Classification</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Self-supervised learning has proved to be a powerful approach to learn image
representations without the need of large labeled datasets. For underwater
robotics, it is of great interest to design computer vision algorithms to
improve perception capabilities such as sonar image classification. Due to the
confidential nature of sonar imaging and the difficulty to interpret sonar
images, it is challenging to create public large labeled sonar datasets to
train supervised learning algorithms. In this work, we investigate the
potential of three self-supervised learning methods (RotNet, Denoising
Autoencoders, and Jigsaw) to learn high-quality sonar image representation
without the need of human labels. We present pre-training and transfer learning
results on real-life sonar image datasets. Our results indicate that
self-supervised pre-training yields classification performance comparable to
supervised pre-training in a few-shot transfer learning setup across all three
methods. Code and self-supervised pre-trained models are be available at
https://github.com/agrija9/ssl-sonar-images
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alan Preciado-Grijalva</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bilal Wehbe</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Miguel Bande Firvida</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Matias Valdenegro-Toro</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>8 pages, 10 figures, with supplementary. LatinX in CV Workshop @ CVPR
  2022 Camera Ready</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.09323v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2204.09323v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  