<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11840v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-12-16T15:03:08Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-12-16T15:03:08Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Sonar-based Deep Learning in Underwater Robotics: Overview, Robustness
  and Challenges</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  With the growing interest in underwater exploration and monitoring,
Autonomous Underwater Vehicles (AUVs) have become essential. The recent
interest in onboard Deep Learning (DL) has advanced real-time environmental
interaction capabilities relying on efficient and accurate vision-based DL
models. However, the predominant use of sonar in underwater environments,
characterized by limited training data and inherent noise, poses challenges to
model robustness. This autonomy improvement raises safety concerns for
deploying such models during underwater operations, potentially leading to
hazardous situations. This paper aims to provide the first comprehensive
overview of sonar-based DL under the scope of robustness. It studies
sonar-based DL perception task models, such as classification, object
detection, segmentation, and SLAM. Furthermore, the paper systematizes
sonar-based state-of-the-art datasets, simulators, and robustness methods such
as neural network verification, out-of-distribution, and adversarial attacks.
This paper highlights the lack of robustness in sonar-based DL research and
suggests future research pathways, notably establishing a baseline sonar-based
dataset and bridging the simulation-to-reality gap.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Martin Aubard</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ana Madureira</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Luís Teixeira</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>José Pinto</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11840v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.11840v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  